脑神经
Cranial nerves.
在高耸的老奥林匹斯山山顶
On old olympus' towering tops
一位友好的维京人种下葡萄和槐花
a friendly viking grew vines and hops.
嗅神经  视神经  动眼神经
Olfactory. Optic. Oculomotor.
迷走神经  副神经
Vagus. Accessory.
水肿成因  A.L.I.V.E
Causes of edema: A.L.I.V.E.
过敏
Allergic...
阴囊肿胀的鉴别诊断
Differentials for swollen scrotum:
T.H.E.A.T.R.E.S
T.H.E.A.T.R.E.S.
英语拼写是  扭转  疝气
English spelling. Torsion, hernia...
附睾囊肿  梅毒
Epididymal cyst. S...syphilis.
不用再背了
Enough with the drilling.
我们都博三了
We're third year.
没有考试了
No more exams.
你又不用每天面对豪斯
You don't have to face House every day.
今天之后  你也不用了
And after today, neither do you.
也不会再泪眼婆娑着回家了
Here's to no more coming home in tears.
这感觉有点像坐过山车
It's kind of like coming to the end
快要到终点了
of an extreme roller-coaster.
虽然被恐惧
Even with the terror,
恶心和颈部受伤所包围
nausea, and whiplash.
但还是会有点依依不舍
I'm a little sad that it's over.
走吧
Let's go.
你的实习记录完成了吗
You got your procedure log?
还没全弄完呢
Oh, I'm not quite done.
还差一个腰椎穿刺要做
I still have one more lumbar puncture.
今天是最后一天了
It's due today.
难不成你不想当医生
Unless you want to blow off becoming a doctor
而是再读一个博士
and get another PHD.
我知道  我会搞定的
I know. I'm gonna get it done.
我还以为你半年前
I thought you'd have that thing finished
就弄完了呢
like six months ago.
我一直很忙
I've been busy.
拜托  克鲁兹
Come on, Cruz.
让给我来吧  我需要完成实习记录
Let me do this. I need it for my log.
等会  你还没完成吗
Wait, you aren't done yet?
我一直很忙
I've been busy.
我能有什么好处
What's in it for me?
帮助同学后的满足感
The satisfaction that comes from helping out a classmate?
票子怎么样
How about cash?
你跟豪斯谈过了吗
Have you talked to House?
现在才早上六点  没几个小时他不会来
It's 6:00 am. He won't be in for a few hours.
我车上存着不少供施舍的硬币
I keep a roll of quarters in the car...
我刚去提交记录表  猜我看到了什么
I just turned in my log and guess what I saw.
诊断科在招人
There's an opening in the diagnostics department.
豪斯想招个实习生
House wants an intern?
他那里从来没有过
He's never had one before.
你该看的出来他不是想要实习生
You gotta figure he doesn't want an intern.
他想要的是你
He wants you.
你一定就是
You must be
十三医生吧
Dr. Thirteen.
我叫莱米·哈德利
Remy Hadley.
很高兴见到你
Nice to meet you.
你回来了
You're back.
你到底出什么事了
What the hell happened to you?
为什么要骗我们说你去罗马了
Why'd you lie about going to Rome?
如果你身无分文
You'd lie too
最后被关到戒毒所
if you bottomed out, ended up in...
你也会撒谎的
drug rehab.
这么尊重我的隐私  十分感谢  豪斯
Thank you, House, for respecting my privacy.
这样隆重的欢迎  我真是受宠若惊
What a perfect reminder that I'm back.
我甚至都不知道你还吸毒
I didn't even know you had a problem.
爱人总是最后一个才知道真相
Loved ones are always the last to know.
死板而被疏远的前男友同样适用
Loved ones and robotic, estranged ex-boyfriends.
我们的病人是凯德尔·皮尔森
Our patient is Kendall Pearson.
16岁雄心勃勃的海盗
16-year-old aspiring pirate.
这个加拿大姑娘想要成为史上最年轻的
She's that canadian kid who's trying to be
驾帆船环游世界的人
the youngest person to sail around the world.
却在昨天的训练中晕倒了
Collapsed yesterday during a practice run.
幸运的是  当时有摄像机
Luckily for us, cameras were there.
赞助商想让我们确定
Corporate sponsors want us to check
在"你太老了没法创纪录"的警钟敲响前
that's she seaworthy before the clock strikes
她是否还能出海
"You're too old to set a record."
给了我们三天期限
Gives us three days.
你就还剩一天了  是吧
You've still only got one, right?
今天是作为学生的最后一天
Last day as a student.
可能是单纯性脱水
Could be simple dehydration.
她跟海警说她感觉到头晕
She told the coast guard she had felt dizzy.
在救援时她的脉搏和血压都正常
Pulse and BP were normal at the time of the rescue.
这不是脱水
It's not dehydration.
你实习的事怎么样了
What about your internship?
今早你签合同了没
You sign up this morning?
其实我还没决定呢
Actually, I'm still deciding.
也许她癫痫发作
Maybe she had a seizure
从而导致了昏迷
and that's what caused her collapse.
海警的报告上说没有头部外伤
Coast guard report says no sign of head trauma.
那她的背部呢
But what about her back?
看
Look.
就在昏倒前
Right before the collapse,
她的背部撞上了栏杆
she hit the small of her back on the railing.
肾上腺受损引起肾上腺素水平不足
Damaged adrenal glands caused adrenal insufficiencies,
进而导致了昏迷
which caused the collapse.
不错
Nice.
连续四小时内每隔十五分钟抽一次血样
Blood draws every 15 minutes for four hours.
监视她的皮质醇含量
Let's track her cortisol.
马斯特斯  不用急
Masters, there's no hurry.
人生没有错误的选择
There's no wrong choices.
至少大家在安慰那些选择错误的人时
At least, that's what they tell people
都是这么说的
who make crappy choices.
你怎么突然对她的未来这么感兴趣
What's with the sudden interest in her future?
当一名铁匠日日夜夜挥洒光阴
You know, a blacksmith who spends this much time
终将一块生铁铸成一柄利刃之后
hammering out a new blade from raw jell-o
就会好奇它最后会落在谁手里
gets curious about who ends up wielding it.
除非是你自己想用
No reason to be curious
不然就没理由好奇
unless you're interested in wielding it yourself.
你想让她在这里实习
You want her to intern here.
而你还真在考虑这事呢
And you're considering this?
在我决定之前
Before I make my decision,
我还有一个腰穿没完成
I still have one more L.P.
我得去做了
I need to get.
所以我要去下急诊室
So I'd like to go to the E.R.
十三  你干嘛不带上马斯特斯
Thirteen, why don't you take Masters
去抽血呢
to do the blood draws?
可以顺便提点她  在我手下做事多牛逼
You can remind her about all the perks of working for me.
甲板后方  左舷
Behind the deck, port side.
如果她肾上腺素水平持续偏低
If her adrenal hormone levels are consistently low,
我们将采用替代疗法
we'll replace them.
周四你就可以出海了
You'll be ready to launch on Thursday.
太棒了
Great.
舱内朝向船头处
Inside cabin facing the bow.
小凯  抱歉  我得跟你妈妈说句话
Sorry, K, I need to borrow mom.
是赞助商吗
The sponsors?
不  库里克的人没事找事
No, Couric's people kicking up a fuss
要求重新安排采访时间
about rescheduling the interview.
那我来吧
I can take over.
船内厨房的天花板
Ceiling of the galley.
答对了  我上一次坐船
Right. The last time I was on a boat
还是在大学新生联谊的时候呢
was my freshman mixer in college.
不过没怎么联谊  光顾着吐了
I didn't so much mix as hurl.
-喝多了吗  -没  我那时才13岁
- Too much to drink? - No, I was 13.
就上大学了吗
And in college?
是啊  我知道  挺稀奇的
Yeah, I know. Weird.
我想说  这太牛了
I was thinking "Cool."
我们十五分钟后再回来抽下一管血
We'll be back for the next blood draw in 15 minutes.
当然  要是你想留在这里
Unless, of course, you'd like to stay,
继续追忆你们遗失的童年也行
and continue bonding over your lost childhoods.
出海前我有一大堆的准备工作要做
Listen, I have a ton of prep work to do to be ready to launch.
能不能快点做完化验
Is there any way we can speed the tests up?
恐怕不行
I'm afraid not.
除非做平板运动试验
Unless you're up for getting on a treadmill.
增加身体负荷
We could stress her body.
观察肾上腺反应
See if her adrenals respond.
只用半个小时就够了
It would only take a half an hour.
-叫我做腰穿的  -去吧  这里我来搞定
- It's about an LP. - Go. I'll handle this.
卡迪医生
Dr. Cuddy,
我一会儿能去办公室找您吗
can I come by your office later?
有件事想咨询一下
I'd love to get some advice.
我一下午都要开会
I'm in meetings all afternoon.
-明天或许有空  -明天啊
- Try me tomorrow. - Tomorrow?
这...
This is...
今天是我作为医科学生的
This is my last day
最后一天了
as a medical student.
我必须做出决定
So I've got this decision to make.
这大概是我职业生涯中最重要的决定
Probably the biggest decision of my career.
甚至可能是我整个人生中最重要的决定
Which means maybe the biggest decision of my life.
尽管  如果我要结婚的话...
Although, I guess, if I get married...
豪斯在招实习生
House has opened up an internship.
你清楚如果你去了
You do realize if you take it,
他很有可能又炒了你吧
he'll probably end up firing you again?
他总是会把我再雇回来的
He's always hired me back.
只要一有机会  他就会不停地
And he'll continue mocking and insulting you,
嘲笑你羞辱你
whatever chance he gets.
但这加强了我的心理承受力
It's certainly toughened me up.
你想让我替他说好话
You're trying to get me to say good things about him.
没  我只想让你自己做决定
No. I'm trying to make you make your own decision,
我好清净会儿
and leave me alone.
和豪斯共事很不错
Working with House is great.
但也很郁闷
and it sucks,
经常会同时有这两种感觉
often simultaneously.
大多数人受不了那种环境
Most people can't work in that environment.
问题是
Question is...
你呢
can you?
谢谢您  卡迪医生
Thanks, Dr. Cuddy.
你把我呼下来  却抢了我的腰穿
You paged me down here and now you're doing my LP?
我等烦了
I got bored waiting.
才两分钟啊
It's been two minutes.
-你都做11次了  -是第14次
- This is your 11th. - 14th.
我说  你的室友是不是
Listen, your roommate,
在跟那个住院医交往啊
is she hooking up with that resident?
我去找豪斯
I got to find House.
马斯特斯  我在急诊
--豪斯
戒毒  这借口真不错
Rehab? Great cover story.
我现在都不能跟他们一起喝酒了
Now I can't ever drink around those guys again,
我和奇斯就靠这个联络感情呢
thus eliminating my main bond with Chase.
把你的抱怨留给那些
Save the attitude for someone
不能为你要回行医执照的人吧
who didn't just get you your medical license back.
凡事都有代价
Price you pay.
你办公室里有只鸡
There's a chicken in your office.
没有
No, there isn't.
你说去戒毒是骗人的吗
You lied about rehab?
-真是太好了  -放松点
- Oh, great. - Relax.
她特别的诚实  也特别的无聊
She's completely honest, but also completely boring.
看好了  不准说出去
Watch this. Don't tell anyone.
当然不会了
Of course not.
你刚做了腰穿吗  为什么不叫我
You did an LP? Why didn't you page me?
不好意思  你想做一个吗
Oh, I'm sorry. Did you want to do one of those?
那你应该开口告诉我呀
You should've spoken up.
你想不想要这份工作
You want the job or not?
经过慎重考虑
I-- after careful consideration,
我决定  接受这份实习
I have decided to accept your offer for an internship.
不错
Great.
我的科室对实习记录的要求不太一样
My department has a slightly different procedure log.
你刚伪造了最后一次记录
Uh, you forged the last one.
我只做过九次腰穿
I only did nine LPs.
-知道怎么做腰穿吗  -当然了
- Do you know how to do an LP? - Of course.
知道怎么把做过九次说成十次吗
Do you know how to do nine LPs and say it was ten?
成熟点儿吧
It's time to grow up.
把表交上  工作就是你的了
Turn that in, the job's yours.
别傻盯着我了  走吧
Stop staring blankly and go.
很显然  咱们的病号
No doubt something horrible has
刚才出事了
just happened to our patient.
就在平板运动试验的时候
Her hand turned completely blue,
她整只手变成淤蓝色了
during the treadmill test.
我们用了血管舒张药
We put her on vasodilators.
血液循环得以恢复才不用截掉手指
Restored enough blood flow so she won't lose any fingers.
排除了肾上腺素不足
Rules out adrenal insufficiency.
豪斯呢  他说在这等他啊
Where's House? He said to meet him here.
他的鸡不见了
His chicken's gone.
大概在阳台上呢
Probably on the balcony.
你知道他有只鸡吗
You knew he had a chicken?
-怎么可能  -在这呢
- How come--? - Down here!
意识丧失  外加她慢慢出淤变蓝
Loss of consciousness. Plus she's slowly turning blue.
我们能排除魔法口香糖吗
Can we rule out magical gum?
心输出量不足会导致这两种症状
Low cardiac output can cause both.
病人可能患有心肌病
Patient possibly has cardiomyopathy.
也许是由汞中毒引起的
Possibly caused by mercury poisoning
就来自她在海上吃的金枪鱼
from all the tuna fish she eats at sea.
你为什么要把鸡爪印
Why are you putting,
印到地板上
chicken footprints on the floor?
威尔森那聪明的混蛋弄了只澳洲黑鸡
That clever bastard Wilson got a hold of an australorp.
你们不知道吗
Hello.
那是所有鸡里面最沉着冷静的
The quietest and calmest of all the chickens.
他真该死
Damn him.
汞中毒可以排除了
Mercury poisoning is out.
红细胞形态正常
Red blood cells have normal morphology.
雷诺病
Raynaud's.
尺动脉血管痉挛可以解释手部症状
Vasospasm in the ulnar artery would explain the hand.
但无法解释意识丧失
But not the loss of consciousness.
脑动脉痉挛可以解释两种症状
Cerebral vasospasm explains both.
脑动脉痉挛说得通
Cerebral vasospasm makes sense.
带上十三
Take Thirteen.
在病人的脑基底动脉注入
Give the patient a calcium channel blocker infusion
钙离子通道阻滞剂
in the basilar artery.
马斯特斯
Masters.
我以为你刚才已经把那个交了
I thought you were going to turn that in.
我  刚才一直在忙病人的事
I... been busy with my patient.
现在不忙吧
You're not busy now.
咕咕  咕咕
Bawwwwwwk bawk.
马斯特斯
Masters.
还没交你的记录表吗
Still haven't turned in your log?
还没完成第十次腰椎穿刺呢
Still haven't gotten my tenth LP.
我在想也许你应该去豪斯那里实习
I was thinking maybe you should take House's internship.
你开始的反应就好像
First you act like it's the equivalent
去那就跟自愿接受水刑一样
of volunteering to be waterboarded
现在你又支持我去了吗
and now you're supporting it?
你很奇怪
You're weird.
你以叠纸飞机为乐
You make paper airplanes for fun
还把它们挂在天花板上
and hang them from the ceiling.
你是爱因斯坦博物馆的会员
You have a membership to the Einstein museum
疯狂的迷恋面部对称学说
and an overbearing obsession with facial symmetry.
那意味着没有患病
It indicates freedom from disease.
从生物学角度上我们都是...
We're biologically programmed--
重点是
The point is
你和别人相处的方式有问题
you rub people the wrong way.
但豪斯可以接受你这种态度
But House is okay with your lack of bedside manner.
也接受你敢于挑战任何人任何观点的行为
He's okay with your willingness to argue any point with anyone
即使是面对资历比你深的人
even if they outrank you.
他还可以接受你怪异的审美观点
He's okay with your peculiar fashion sense.
这很奇怪吗
It's peculiar?
豪斯不觉得你诡异
House doesn't think you're weird,
这点已经很诡异了
which is weird,
但这是好事
but good weird.
那是只鸡吗
Is that a chicken?
我看是澳洲黑鸡
I think it's an australorp.
我要去检查病人了
I'm gonna go check on my patient.
有人能跟我解释下
Can someone please explain to me
豪斯和威尔森
what House and Wilson
在拿那些鸡做什么吗
are doing with those chickens?
他们在赌谁在医院里养的鸡
They have a bet to see who can keep a chicken
会最后被保安发现
in the hospital the longest without getting busted by security.
已通过椎动脉
Advancing past the vertebral artery.
他们为什么要这么做呢
And why are they doing this?
他俩买鸡的地方只剩一头猪了
The place they bought them only had one pig.
很高兴今天过后你还会留在这里
I'm glad you're gonna be sticking around after today.
真的吗  你希望我留下来
Really? You want me to stay?
部门里能有不同观点是好事
It's good to add a different perspective to the department.
至少有人能记住除了豪斯的法则外
Someone who still remembers there are rules
还有其他准则要遵守
other than House's.
如果我不按豪斯的规矩做
If I don't play by House's rules,
他不会让我加入的
he won't let me in.
想个办法糊弄他
Find a way around them.
那我就得对他撒谎  那还是得撒谎
I'd have to lie to him, which is still lying.
用谎言掩盖谎言
Lying about a lie,
也算是陈述事实了
that's practically telling the truth.
导管插进去了
Catheter's in.
开始钙离子通道阻滞剂静脉滴注
Start the calcium channel blocker drip.
就是说我需要再做一次腰椎穿刺
Means I need another LP.
你太幸运了  我正好知道谁需要做
Luckily, I know where you can get one.
你能搞定吗  我们走
You good here? Let's go.
插入过程不错  很熟练
Decent stick. Very smooth.
听上去你做过好几次了
Sounds like you've had a few of these.
似乎我哪壶不开提哪壶了
Suppose that comes with the territory.
我有亨廷顿病
I have huntington's.
不用为我的事大惊小怪
No need to get hushed and solemn about it.
为什么要撒谎说你去戒毒了呢
Why are you lying about rehab?
因为我不想让别人知道
Because the real reason I was gone
我离开的真正原因
is not something I want to share.
你就不能直说吗
Couldn't you just say that?
对福曼和其他人来说这理由应该足够了
Should be enough for Foreman and the others.
你在这工作多久了
How long have you worked here?
豪斯手下的这些人
House's people have personalities
都爱管闲事
that range from nosy
在探究你隐私时还振振有词
to "pardon me while I do this cavity search".
你觉得处事方法不同的人
Do you think there's room for someone
在他手下会有生存空间吗
who does things differently?
没有
No.
除非豪斯认为那是他想要的
Not unless House decides that's what he wants.
导管移出时
During catheter removal,
在大脑中线处得到了很好的图像
I got a good look at her cerebral midline.
松果体有钙化
Pineal gland is calcified.
病例解决了
Case closed.
我会开始进行激素治疗
I'll start her on hormone therapy.
让她尽快出院
Ship her out.
我把记录表交了
I handed in my log.
你在交表的路上
On your way to do that,
是不是恰巧帮十三做了腰椎穿刺
did you happen to stop and give thirteen an LP?
十三表情僵硬  瞳孔缩小
Thirteen's stiff gate, small pupils,
以及她试图隐藏的头痛出卖了你
and the raging headache she's hiding gave you away.
没错  而且我还是违反规定了
Yes. And I still broke a rule.
我的规定
My rule.
是让你藐视权威  而不是我
Told you to defy the man. Not this man.
我不喜欢骗人到底有什么不对
Why is it so wrong that I don't like to cheat?
我们可以走了吗
Can we go?
不行
No.
不喜欢骗人没问题
Not liking it is fine.
不喜欢就不做了就是幼稚
Not doing what you don't like makes you an eight-year-old.
糟蹋自己的天分
Wastes your potential.
你想让我变得像你一样  这不可能
You want me to be like you. It's not going to happen.
我根本不想让你变得像我
That's the last thing I want,
因为这样我们就都不再是独一无二的了
cause then neither one of us would be exceptional.
你觉得我是独一无二的吗
You think I'm exceptional?
现在不了
Not anymore.
我可以在不妥协的情况下做好我的工作
I can do my job without compromising.
不  你不能
No, you can't,
因为我不会让你这么做
cause I'm not gonna let you.
实习的机会吹了
Internship's gone.
该和马斯特斯说再见了
It's time for Masters to say good-bye.
好好当个外科医生吧
Enjoy being a surgeon.
你会干得不错的
You'll be fine.
外科学
Surgery.
解剖学
Anatomy.
锁骨下动脉分支
Branches off the subclavian artery.
维他命C和D以及VIT
Vitamin C and D. V-I-T
维他命V指椎动脉  I指颈内动脉
Vitamin. V: vertebral. I: internal carotid--
胸廓内动脉  是指胸廓内动脉
internal thoracic. Internal thoracic.
T指甲状颈干
T: thyrocervical.
C指肋颈干
C: costocervical.
玛莎·M·马斯特斯  就是我了
Martha.M.Masters. That's me.
我要成为一名外科医生了
I'm gonna be a surgeon.
下一位
Next.
欢迎来到普林斯顿教学医院开始外科实习
Welcome to your surgical internship at P.P.T.H.
高年资住院医生就站在你们身后
The senior residents stand behind you.
我们很快就会相互熟悉了
We'll all get to know each other soon enough.
拿个甜甜圈  然后去工作吧
Grab a donut and get to work.
没有甜甜圈了
We're out of donuts.
那就  开始工作吧
Then, uh, get to work.
有点渗出
Little oozing.
-分离左锁骨下动脉  -抽吸一下
- Isolated the left subclavian. - Suction.
你得好好抽吸一下  我什么也看不见
You got to do better than that. Can't see a thing.
推氯化钙
Push calcium chloride.
这样会刺激血小板
It will supercharge the platelets
加强凝血能力
and increase the clotting.
两支氯化钙
Two AMPs calcium chloride.
让血库准备
Tell the blood bank to set up
三单位的袋装红细胞
three units of packed red cells.
术野清晰了
Field is clear.
很好
Nice.
一般来说
Generally speaking,
实习生是不该说话的
pledges aren't supposed to talk
除非他们有问题要问
unless they ask a question.
这是因为  一般来说
That's because, generally speaking,
实习生都吐不出什么好话
pledges don't have anything to say.
这个K.P
Um, K.P.
是那个凯德尔·皮尔森吗
Is that patient Kendall Pearson?
我以为她出院了
I thought she was discharged.
那是豪斯的病例
Mm. It's a House case.
我从来搞不懂他要做什么
I never know what that guy's up to.
我想要你参加我的供体肺摘取手术
I want you to scrub in on my lung harvest.
但这是我第一天实习
But it's my first day.
我知道  我在场的
Yes, I know. I was there.
十五分钟内擦洗准备好
Be scrubbed and ready in 15 minutes.
出什么事了
What happened?
你们不是出院回家了么
Last I heard, you were going home.
凯德尔在停车场晕倒了
Kendall collapsed in the parking lot.
他们在做什么交感神经切除术
They're doing something called a "Sympathectomy".
她一定是有由肾脏的内脏神经孤独兴奋
She must've had a hypertensive crisis
引起的高血压危象
caused by a neural overstimulation in her kidneys.
所以他们在切除神经
So they're cutting the nerves.
就像是切除通往引擎的油管
It's like cutting the gas line to an engine.
没错  和陶博医生说的差不多
Yeah, sounds like what Dr. Taub said.
他说这只是个小手术  但是
Said it's basic surgery, but...
没错
It is.
你们应该还能在三十六小时后启航
You should still be on pace for a launch in 36 hours.
她妈妈正在准备船上的物品呢
Her mom's packing the boat now.
我本应该去买些干冰的
I'm supposed to pick up some dry ice.
但是
But...
可留在这里你也帮不上忙啊
Nothing you can do for her here.
我们只是在尽力帮女儿实现梦想
We're just trying to help our daughter reach her dream.
她很与众不同
She's different.
所以你们也得与众不同才行
So you have to be different.
我会确保她没事的
I'll make sure she's okay.
谢谢
Thanks.
你可以看到左肺完整的小叶结构
You can see the full lobular structure of the left lung.
无名动脉分叉
Bifurcate innominate artery.
我还从没看过这个呢
I've never seen one of those before.
马斯特斯  拿着这个
Hold this, Masters.
肋骨牵开器
Rib spreaders.
我从这调用一名巡回护士你们有意见吗
You guys okay if I pull a circulating nurse?
第十术间出问题了
We got a train wreck in O.R. Ten.
没问题
You got it.
近端接好了
Proximal end attached.
能让别人帮我拿下牵拉器吗
Can someone take the retractors from me?
不行
Not really.
我得去厕所
I have to use the bathroom.
我知道你是新手  但你也太离谱了
I know you're a rookie, but you got to be kidding.
-我真忍不住了  -等会再说
- I'm not. - It can wait.
我快忍不住了
I'm gonna have an accident.
队里的下一位  拿好
Next one in line, grab it.
-怎么了  -低血压
- What's wrong?  - Hypotension.
心排血量降低
Low cardiac output.
置入Swan-Ganz导管
Float the Swan.
你不是自己有手术吗
Don't you have your own surgery?
我溜出来了  我告诉他们我要去厕所
I took a break. I told them I had to pee.
你撒谎了
You lied.
一个小谎  但你上道了
Small one. But it's a gateway lie.
我关心这位病人
I care about the patient.
又撒了一个谎
Another lie.
你在乎的是自己是否独一无二
You care about being exceptional.
我和她父亲说过我会照顾好她的
I told her dad I was gonna take care of her.
第三个谎言
A third lie.
你真是越来越上道了
Welcome to the slippery slope.
右房压八毫米汞柱
Ra is 8.
心房心室之间的压力均衡
Equalization of pressures.
就是说她患了缩窄性心包炎
Means she has restrictive pericarditis.
外加钙化的松果体
Add that to a calcified pineal gland.
什么情况下钙化的松果体
When is a calcified pineal gland
不是真正的钙化的松果体
not a calcified pineal gland?
我知道理论上不可能  但
I realize, technically, it's never, but--
是肉芽肿的时候
When it's a granuloma.
是韦格纳氏肉芽肿
It's Wegener's.
得给她用类固醇治疗
We should start her on steroids.
但是她肌酸激酶很高
But she had a high CK.
韦格纳氏肉芽肿解释不了
Wegener's wouldn't explain the--
脱水解释的通
Dehydration does.
是的  但是钙化的松果体
Yes. But the calcified pineal
可能是结节病
could be sarcoidosis.
你撒谎说要上厕所  就得我倾心了
You had me at "I had to pee".
但是十三是对的
But Thirteen's right.
给她用三倍剂量的免疫抑制剂
Start her on three fold immunosuppressants.
马斯特斯  如果想和我争论此事的话
Masters, if you want to fight me on this,
填个会诊表格你就能留下跟进这病例了
fill out a consult form so you can stick around.
欢迎回归
Welcome back.
我没有要回来
I'm not back!
我只待到这个病例结束
I'll just be staying for this case.
你还真是个大师级谎话精啊
You got really good at this lying thing.
希望这只是智者的一次失误
Hope it was one hell of a whiz.
我碰到了豪斯医生
I ran into Dr. House.
他要求我为他的病人做外科会诊
He requested a surgical consult for his patient.
豪斯从来不会要求会诊
House never asks for a consult.
关于这个病例
Something about this case,
他需要额外的帮助
he needed a little more help.
你外科实习的第一天
First day of your surgical internship,
你就想被外借到其他部门去
you want to be loaned out to another department.
有趣的职业举动啊
Interesting career move.
把表格放到我办公室
Drop the form by my office.
不要去太久
Don't stay away too long.
我已经开始渐渐忘记你了
I'm already well on my way to forgetting you.
我请你们两位美女去喝一杯怎么样
How about I take both you lovely ladies out for a drink?
我想去来着  但我觉得你是个白痴
I'd love to. Except I think you're a cretin.
她最后一次搭着横杠是在芭蕾课上
And the last time she was at a bar was ballet class.
我没上过
I didn't take--
很好笑
Oh. That's funny.
我要留在这里给豪斯的病人做些化验
I'm gonna stay and run a few extra tests on House's patient.
我觉得有一个实验数据不太对
This one lab value doesn't make sense to me.
你要回豪斯那里吗
You're back with House?
就这个病例  我不会久留的
Mm. Just this one case. I'm not staying.
要能和他共事叫我杀人都愿意
I would kill for a chance to work with him.
比如剥了你的皮再穿上你的皮囊伪装成你
Like, literally skin you and wear you as a disguise.
你的鸡肉是要劲脆的还是原味的
You want yours extra crispy or original recipe?
鸡
Chickens!
你因家禽得过病吗
You ever get sick from poultry?
几个月前
Um, a few months ago
因为一罐鸡肉罐头  我爸还嘲笑我
from this pheasant-in-a-can my dad got me as a joke.
你觉得那是我生病的原因吗
You think that's why I'm sick?
我觉得那个罐子里充满了
I think that can was chock-full
沙门氏菌的病菌
of a bacteria called salmonella enteritis,
喜欢驻留在骨头上
likes to hang out in the bones.
感觉紧张或疼痛时告诉我
Let me know if any of this is tender or painful.
这个细菌什么的
Um, this bacteria thing,
是好消息还是坏消息
is this good news or bad?
如果我说的没错
Well, if I'm right,
那么你只需要服用抗生素就可以了
that means all you'll need are antibiotics.
你就能恢复"船形"[井然有序  意指恢复健康]
And you'll be, uh, well, shipshape.
抱歉  没忍住
Sorry. Couldn't resist.
你一直都认为航海是你真正想做的事吗
Did you always know that sailing was it for you?
是适合自己的吗
That it was the right thing?
我直到十岁才开始航海
Didn't even start till I was ten.
开始时  我并不热衷于此
And at first, I was not a fan.
很明显航海有许多惹人厌的地方
Certainly there's plenty not to like about sailing.
但你现在却如此痴迷
But now that you're so into it...
不  仍然有很多关于航海的事是我讨厌的
Oh, no, there's still plenty of things I hate about it.
我讨厌弄湿自己  讨厌寒冷
I hate being wet. I hate being cold.
我讨厌什么都没得吃只能吃冻干的食物
I hate eating nothing but freeze-dried food.
举双脚表赞同
That is quite the endorsement.
航海很棒
Sailing is amazing.
但并不是说我喜欢待在船上的分分秒秒
But doesn't mean I love every second on the boat.
做自己之所爱即是要处理自己之所不爱
Doing what you love means dealing with things you don't.
如果没有要克服的困难
If there were nothing to overcome,
可能就没有那么
it might not be that--
沙门氏菌这个诊断不错啊
Salmonella enteritis is a nice catch.
谢谢  开始看软组织窗
Thanks. Starting on the soft tissue windows.
这病例结束  你就回外科吗
Once this case is over, you going back to surgery?
是这么打算的
That's the plan.
我觉得你这样做是在犯错
I think that's a mistake.
我觉得你应该回外科
I think you should go back to surgery.
我刚就是这么说的
I just said I was.
不对  你说那是你的打算
No. You said it was your plan.
也就是说豪斯可能是对的
Which means House might be right.
你可能是在欺骗自己
And you might be lying to yourself.
有那么可怕吗
Would it be so terrible?
你选择了跟豪斯而不是去外科
You chose House over surgery.
在这里的经历改变了我
My time here changed me
我身边的人并不都认为这是种好的转变
in ways not everyone in my life thought was for the better.
没有肿块  接下来看骨窗
No masses. Moving on to bone windows.
那些人说的对吗
Are those people right?
我觉得你一旦变了
I think when you do change,
想再回到过去就不那么简单了
it's not so simple to go back.
那里
There.
肱骨那边
In the humerus.
看着不像是感染
Doesn't look like an infection.
因为看着像肿瘤
That's because it looks like cancer.
你得了淋巴肉瘤
You have lymphoid sarcoma.
这癌症位于你手臂骨头上
A cancer in the bone in your arm.
我会好起来吗
Am I going to be okay?
这种癌症是可治愈的
It's a treatable cancer.
但治疗包括截去你的手臂
But part of that treatment involves amputating your arm.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
没有其它的了吗
There's nothing else?
截肢后需做化疗和放疗
We can do chemo and radiation after the amputation.
不是说后续其它  我是说其它选择
I don't mean after. I mean instead of.
如果我赶快出院  我还有时间去破纪录
If I leave soon, I still have time to break the record.
宝贝  你不是说真的吧
Honey, you can't be serious.
我感觉没事啊
I feel fine.
昨晚  他们还以为是感染呢
Last night, they thought it was an infection.
确诊是癌症
We know it's cancer.
活检了三次
We ran the biopsy three times.
你不知道多快
You don't know how fast--
延迟手术
Postponing the surgery
会提高癌细胞扩散的风险
could increase the likelihood that the cancer will spread.
凯德尔  你需要考虑考虑医生说的
Kendall, you need to think about what the doctor's saying.
你考虑的是帆船航海
I'm thinking about the sail.
我十岁起就这样
Like I have since I was ten.
别把它夺走
Don't take this away from me.
就一个月
It's just a month.
我会特别小心
I can take extra precautions.
我会每天和你们网络通话
I'll skype you every day
要有状况我可以飞回来
and I can fly back if something goes wrong.
她在拿生命冒险
She'll be risking her life.
我们一家想私下谈谈
I think we need to discuss this as a family.
你在考虑她说的话吗
You're considering this?
你女儿的情况
Your daughter's condition--
谢谢你  马斯特斯医生
Thank you, Dr. Masters.
她心意已决  想明天就起航
She's not budging. She wants to launch tomorrow.
她是未成年人
She's a minor.
只要监护人签了同意书  我们就能手术
You sign the consent form, we can do the surgery.
截肢会是
Amputation can be an emo--
她说服了她母亲
She's talked my wife into agreeing with her.
一名家长签字就行
One parent's signature is enough.
她需要你尽父亲之职
She needs you to be a parent.
你是在让我拆散我的家庭
You're asking me to blow up my family.
我是在让你挽救你的家庭
I'm asking you to save your family.
她第一次独自横穿大西洋时
On her first solo atlantic crossing,
就和我们闹上法庭
she scheduled a court date
要脱离父母监护
to become an emancipated minor.
她会再来一次  并且还会成功
She'll do it again and she'll win.
我同不同意她依旧会去做
She is gonna do what she's gonna do with or without me.
我宁愿当个支持她的父亲
I'd rather have it be with.
我没辙了
I'm stuck.
不  你没有
No, you're not.
病例解决了  回外科实习去吧
Case is over. You're back to surgery.
衔回来
And fetch.
好孩子
Oh, that's a good boy.
Hey, good boy.
没人去阻止凯德尔航海
No one will stop Kendall's sail.
你得介入了
You need to step in.
门上写着我是诊断医师
Sign on the door says I'm a diagnostician.
诊断出来就没我的事了
Cool diagnosis means I'm finished.
她会死的
She could die.
我很确信法律规定
Pretty sure the law of the land states
每个人都有权当傻瓜
that everyone has the right to be an idiot.
应该是宪法第二修正案  衔回来
I think it's the second amendment. Fetch!
衔过来  孩子
Bring it here, boy.
谁是好孩子
Who's a good boy?
你一直对虚伪嗤之以鼻
You are constantly railing against hypocrisy,
逼别人去面对现实
forcing people to face the truth.
这次却坐视不理吗
This time nothing?
对  因为他们已经面对现实了
Yeah. 'Cause they faced the truth.
并做了一个
And made a decision
极可能害死自己女儿的决定
that will in all likelihood kill their daughter.
我无所谓
I'm fine with that.
我想要诊断结果  有了
I wanted a diagnosis. I got it.
你想要什么
What do you want?
我不想她死
I don't want her to die.
那就违规行事呗
Break the rules.
我不能
I can't.
看样子对你来说
So coloring inside the lines is more important to you
墨守成规比救这女孩更重要
than saving this girl's life?
我弄错了一件事
I was wrong about one thing,
你不过是个常人
you are not exceptional.
衔回来
And fetch!
好孩子
Ho ho ho. Oh, that's a good boy.
好孩子  好孩子
Good boy. Good boy.
威尔森医生
Dr. Wilson.
关于一名癌症病人的事
Um, I'd like to get your advice
我想听听你意见
about a cancer patient.
凯德尔·皮尔森  肿瘤科查过房
Kendall Pearson. Oncology rounds.
大家都在谈论
Everyone's talking about it.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
没事  我背有点不舒服
Yeah, my back's acting up.
换你会怎么做呢
So what would you do?
我会继续劝说她手术
I would keep trying to convince her to have the surgery.
要是她还是拒绝呢
And if she kept saying no?
我会继续
I would just keep--
继续  尝试
keep--keep trying.
我知道下面有只鸡
I know there's a chicken under there.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank god.
它都啄坏我一双鞋了
It's pecked through one pair of my loafers.
所以你就只是劝说吗
So that's all you'd do?
你只能劝说
That's all you can do.
是吗
Is it?
这不是豪斯的那只鸡吗
Isn't that House's chicken?
恶心的畜生
Disgusting beasts.
搞不懂自己为什么同意打这赌
I don't know why I ever agreed to this bet.
那就退出呗
So call it off.
并输掉二十美元吗
And lose $20?
豪斯当年也处于凯德尔一样的处境
Listen, House was in the exact same situation Kendall's in.
他得做手术  但他不想做
He needed surgery, but he didn't want it.
他陷入诱导昏迷后
Once he was in medically-induced coma,
他女友代其签了同意书
his girlfriend signed the consent form as his proxy.
医院违背他的意愿做了手术
They went ahead with the surgery against his will.
虽说算是救了他的命
Probably saved his life.
所以她做得对
So she did the right thing?
答案取决于你问谁
Depends on who you ask.
衔回来
Fetch!
不  不
No! No!
请问
Excuse me.
这只鸡是哪位的
Who's responsible for this chicken?
谁知道这只鸡是谁的
Does anyone know who owns the chicken?
这只鸟类
That bird belongs to...
是格利高里·豪斯医生的
Dr. Gregory House.
你需要做这手术
You need to do this surgery.
我会做的
I will.
现在就做
Now.
这事我们已经讨论过了
We've been through this.
我今天就出院
I'm leaving today.
不过是项纪录而已
It's a stupid record.
不是纪录的问题
It's not about the record.
我以前和人竞赛的时候
I used to race against other people.
驾最慢的船也能得第一
I could have the slowest boat in the fleet and I'd win.
那么你是为了证明自己比别人优秀吗
So it's about being better than everyone else?
这与其他任何人无关  只是我自己
It has nothing to do with anybody except me.
其他帆船手都觉得我是疯子
The other racers would think I was crazy.
我会把帆转到匪夷所思的角度出航
I'd set off on some tacking angle
他们完全不能理解
that made no sense to them
因为他们无法了解我的感觉
because they couldn't see what I saw.
我能在风向改变之前
I could sense the changes in the wind
就察觉到变化
before they even happened.
当你站到顶峰  游戏规则就不同了
At the top of the game, you play by different rules.
这药会有点刺激血管
Medicine's gonna burn a little bit.
心动过缓  三度房室传导阻滞
Bradycardic arrest. Third degree heart block.
很可能是伴癌综合征
Likely paraneoplastic syndrome.
得把她送到手术室
We need to get her to the O.R.
做心律调整或者血浆置换
for pacemaker or plasmapheresis.
怎么回事
What's going on?
癌症导致她心跳变缓
The cancer is causing her heart to slow down.
我们需要把她送到手术室治疗
We have to get her to the O.R. and treat her.
这种情况正是我担心的
This is what I was worried about.
如果航行中发生这种事  她会丧命
If this had happened at sea, she would be dead.
我的上帝
Oh, my god.
我们需要你们签了同意书
We need you to sign the consent form.
授权我们截断她的手臂
Authorize us to amputate her arm.
锁骨下静脉通路建立
Subclavian access established.
-临时起搏器就位  -没有必要
- Temporary pacer ready. - Don't need it.
注射氯化钙
Push calcium chloride.
房室传导阻滞就会好转
It'll fix the heart block.
心动过缓是我引发的
Bradycardia was me.
是你干的
You did this?
她父母签了同意书
Parents signed the consent form.
做截肢
Amputate her arm.
发生什么事了
What happened?
你心脏病发作
You had a cardiac episode
我们不得不进行手术
that required us to bring you into the O.R.
现在危机已经解除  但是
That crisis resolved, but...
你们做了什么  你们做了什么
What did you do? What did you do?
手术过程中
During surgery,
我们在你颈部淋巴结发现癌细胞
we found cancer in a lymph node in your neck.
所以你们砍掉了我的胳膊
So you cut off my arm?
癌症已经开始扩散
Cancer was already spreading.
只能如此
It had to be done.
我说了我不想这样
I told you I didn't want this.
如果等到航行结束再手术
If we had waited until after the sail was over
就为时已晚了
you would have died.
那项记录就是我的一切
That record. That was everything.
它不是你的一切
It wasn't everything.
你还有生活  有未来
You have a life. A future.
都说好了的  你们怎么可以这样
You weren't supposed to do this. How could you?
因为我们爱你
Because we love you.
我恨你们
I hate you.
我恨你们两个
I hate both of you.
好了
Okay.
我的胳膊
My arm.
马斯特斯医生  谢谢你
Dr. Masters, thank you.
某人撅着嘴闷闷不乐呀
Someone has got their pouty face on.
我做了任何头脑清醒的医生都不会做的事
I did things no doctor in their right mind would do.
很好
Good.
我操纵  说谎  伪造  偷窃
I manipulated, lied, forged, stole.
我不想知道细节
I don't want to know the specifics.
万一被传讯就不好了
Might be called to testify.
我当时相信自己是对的所以才打破规则
I broke the rules because I believed I was right.
你是对的
You were right.
那我为什么没有感到舒心如意
Then why don't I feel good or satisfied?
反而恶心想吐
Instead, I just feel like throwing up.
所以你跟着我是想问时常打破规则的我
And you're following me to ask how I break the rules
为何依旧风度翩翩
and maintain my rosy demeanor.
我不是为了自己高兴才那样做
I didn't do it to be happy.
我只是以为我会好过
I just thought I would be.
人生岂能事事如意
You can't always get what you want.
对捣鬼冠军致敬
To the victor of the spoils.
你的鸡康复得如何了
Your bird recover okay?
身体上恢复了
Physically, yes.
感情上很受伤
Emotionally, it was a long night.
下周玩雪貂
Next week ferrets?
豪斯
House.
我做不到
I can't do it.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
去外科吗
Surgery?
我不知道我以后要做什么
I...don't know what I'm going to do.
我只知道我不想留在这里
But I do know I don't want to be here.
你的生活不会再回归单纯
Nothing will ever be simple again.
我无所谓
I'm fine with that.
生活岂能事事如意*
*You can't always get what you want
凡事尽力*
*And if you try sometime
总能找到*
*You'll find
真心所需*
*You'll get what you need